Guide to Montana Public Service Commission, Utilities Division records 1913-1986
Montana Historical Society
- Telephone Companies, 1914-1980
  - Annual Reports
    - Reed Point: Farmers Cooperative Telephone Company, 1923-1949 (Box-folder 26 / 36)
    - Ronan: Flathead Independent Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1925-1968 (Box-folder 27 / 1-2)
    - Rosebud Mutual Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926; includes Lame Deer), 1919-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 3)
    - Rudyard: Goldstone, Rudyard, Brinkman Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926; renamed Rudyard Telephone Company), 1924-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 4)
    - Ryegate: Central Montana Telephone Company, 1916 (Box-folder 27 / 5)
    - Saco and Malta: Mutual Telephone Company of Saco, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 27 / 6)
    - St. Ignatius Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1938-1964; sold to Treasure State Telephone Company, 1952-1965 (Box-folder 27 / 7)
    - St. Ignatius: Treasure State Telephone Company, 1967, 1969 (Box-folder 27 / 8)
    - Savage: Midway Telephone Company, 1918-1920 (Box-folder 27 / 9)
    - Scobey: Northeastern Montana Telephone Cooperative (includes rate schedule, 1954), 1958 (Box-folder 27 / 10)
    - Shelby: Northern Telephone Association, 1956-1957 (Box-folder 27 / 11)
    - Sheridan: Mill Creek Telephone Company, 1918, 1924, 1926 (Box-folder 27 / 12)
    - Simms Telephone Company, 1918-1922 (Box-folder 27 / 13)
    - Springdale: Duck Creek Telephone Company, 1914, 1923, 1926 (Box-folder 27 / 14)
    - Stevensville: Sage Brush Telephone Company, 1923-1924 (Box-folder 27 / 15)
    - Sunburst Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1928; sold to Northern Telephone Association), 1928-1954 (Box-folder 27 / 16)
    - Sunburst: Northern Telephone Association, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 27 / 17)
    - Superior: A. P. Johnston Local Telephone Line (includes rate schedule, 1926; sold by his estate at sheriff's sale), 1924-1931 (Box-folder 27 / 18)
    - Superior Telephone Company (name changed to Superior Electric and Water Works), 1931-1950 (Box-folder 27 / 19)
    - Superior: Telephone Utility of the Montana Power Company, 1931-1950 (Box-folder 27 / 20)
    - Sweetgrass Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926, 1930), 1920-1921, 1926-1943 (Box-folder 27 / 21)
    - Townsend: Upper Valley Telephone Company, 1919 (Box-folder 27 / 22)
    - Troy Telephone Company (service taken over by Libby-Troy Telephone Company), 1914-1919 (Box-folder 27 / 23)
    - Valier: Francis Heights Telephone Company (exempted from annual reports, 1926), 1917-1926 (Box-folder 27 / 24)
    - Vida-Wolf Point Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1926-1944 (Box-folder 27 / 25)
    - Westby Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1939; sold to Northeast Montana Telephone Cooperative Association), 1934-1954 (Box-folder 27 / 26)
    - White Sulphur Springs: Springs Exchange (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 27)
    - Whitlash: Sweet Grass Hills Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1926-1948), 1924-1949 (Box-folder 27 / 28)
    - Whitewater: Mutual Telephone Company of Saco (includes rate schedules, 1926; moved to Forks), 1919-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 29)
    - Wibaux: Golden Valley Telephone Company (includes contracts, 1912-1915; service from Beach, UNDATED), 1919-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 30)
    - Wilsall: East Flathead Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1918-1939 (Box-folder 27 / 31)
    - Wilsall Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1917, 1926), 1924-1928 (Box-folder 27 / 32)
    - Wilsall: Bohart Telephone Company, 1926 (Box-folder 27 / 33)
    - Winnett: Burt Sisters (includes rate schedule, 1926), 1924-1959 (Box-folder 27 / 34)
    - Wisdom: Southern Montana Telephone Company (moved from Dillon), 1939-1969 (Box-folder 27 / 35)
    - Wise River: Dewey Telephone Company, 1916-1920, 1926 (Box-folder 27 / 36)
    - Worden: Farmers Telephone Company (includes rate schedule, 1915), 1913, 1916 (Box-folder 27 / 37)
    - Worden: Riverside Telephone Company (includes rate schedules, 1925-1926), 1916-1946 (Box-folder 27 / 38)
    - Worden: Project Telephone Company, 1947-1969 (Box-folder 27 / 39)
  - Accident Reports
    - Statewide: Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Company, 1956-1966, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 27 / 40)
- Telephone Answering Services, Paging Services, and Mobile Phone Companies, 1962-1985
  - Reports: largely rate schdules
    - Able Answering Service (Great Falls; becomes Aircall Inc.), 1965-1969 (Box-folder 27a / 1)
    - Advanced Electronics Inc. (Billings), 1976-1985 (Box-folder 27a / 2)
    - Aircall Inc. (Great Falls), 1971-1985 (Box-folder 27a / 3)
    - Answering by Birken / Birken's Radio Service (Billings), 1965-1984 (Box-folder 27a / 4)
    - Beaverhead Electronics (Dillon), 1980 (Box-folder 27a / 5)
    - Business Communications Company (Great Falls), 1977-1983 (Box-folder 27a / 6)
    - Capital Answering Service (Helena), 1963-1982 (Box-folder 27a / 7)
    - Capital Communications (Helena), 1984 (Box-folder 27a / 8)
    - Communication Services (Billings), 1980 (Box-folder 27a / 9)
    - Conrad Communication (Conrad), 1977-1982 (Box-folder 27a / 10)
    - Datacom (Madison, Wisc.), 1983 (Box-folder 27a / 11)
    - Havre Answering Service (Havre), 1976-1983 (Box-folder 27a / 12)
    - Industrial Electronics and Automation Company (Billings; becomes Treasure State Mobile Phone), 1972-1985 (Box-folder 27a / 13)
    - Mathews Telephone Answerings Service (Great Falls), 1971-1980 (Box-folder 27a / 14)
    - Missoula Communications Service (Missoula; becomes Montana Communications), 1962-1964 (Box-folder 27a / 15)
    - Montana Communications (Missoula; becomes Industrial Electronics and Automation Company), 1970-1972 (Box-folder 27a / 16)
    - MTI (Mountain Telecommunications Inc., Butte; reseller), 1983 (Box-folder 27a / 17)
    - NR Recording and Communications Inc. (Great Falls), 1980 (Box-folder 27a / 18)
    - Omnicom (Missoula), 1973-1982 (Box-folder 27a / 19)
    - PacWest Telecomm Inc. (Stockton, Calif.), 1982 (Box-folder 27a / 20)
    - Richards Answering Service (Helena; taken over by Capital Answering Service), 1975-1979 (Box-folder 27a / 21)
    - Tel-Com Paging (Glendive), 1980 (Box-folder 27a / 22)
    - Tel-Com Systems (Miles City; d/b/a Cottage Fone Answering), 1980 (Box-folder 27a / 23)
    - Tri-Star Communications (Plevna), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 27a / 24)
    - West Montana Mobile Telephone (Missoula), 1970-1980 (Box-folder 27a / 25)
    - Wolf Point Answering Service (Wolf Point), 1981-1983 (Box-folder 27a / 26)
    - Worland Services (Worland, Wyo.), 1975 (Box-folder 27a / 27)
    - Wymo Communications (Billings), 1979-1984 (Box-folder 27a / 28)
- Oil Pipeline Companies, 1930-1940, 1959-1986
  - Reports: Annual Reports and Monthly Statements of Operations
    - Big West Oil Company of Montana (natural gas pipeline, Kevin), 1933-1940 (Box-folder 28 / 1)
    - Cenex Pipeline Company (1970-1973 are monthly statements of operations), 1960-1973 (Box-folder 28 / 2-4)
    - Continental Pipe Line Company (1970-1984 are monthly statements of operations), 1960-1984 (Box-folder 28 / 5-15)
    - Crude Oil Pipeline Inc., 1960-1961 (Box-folder 28 / 16)
    - Darling Gathering System (sold to Producers Pipeline Company), 1965 (Box-folder 28 / 17)
    - Deep Rock Oil Corp., 1954 (Box-folder 28 / 18)
    - Exxon Pipeline Company (formerly Humble Pipe Line Company; monthly statements of operations only), 1973-1974 (Box-folder 28 / 19)
    - Gallatin Natural Gas Company (pipeline company), 1930-1933 (Box-folder 28 / 20)
    - Glacier Pipe Line Company, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 28 / 21-23)
    - Homestake Oil and Gas Company, 1968-1981 (Box-folder 28 / 24)
    - Humble Pipe Line Company (becomes Exxon Pipeline Company; 1969-1970 are monthly statements of operations), 1961-1972 (Box-folder 28 / 25-29)
    - Hunt Petroleum Corp. Pipe Line, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 28 / 30)
    - Husky Pipeline Company, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 29 / 1)
    - Interstate Oil Pipe Line Company (merged into Humble Pipe Line Company), 1945-1961 (Box-folder 29 / 2-3)
    - Johnston's Fuel Lines Inc., 1962 (Box-folder 29 / 4)
    - Kent Oil Company, 1955 (Box-folder 29 / 5)
    - Marathon Pipe Line Company (1969-1972 are monthly statements of operations), 1960-1972 (Box-folder 29 / 6-8)
    - Ohio Oil Company (rates and valuations), 1943-1959 (Box-folder 29 / 9)
    - Phillips Petroleum Company (1969-1986 are monthly statements of operations), 1959-1986 (Box-folder 29 / 10-23)
    - Powderriver Pipeline Company (succeeded by Crude Oil Pipeline Company), 1955-1960 (Box-folder 29 / 24)
    - Producers Pipe Line Company (sold to Western Pipeline Company), 1966-1969 (Box-folder 29 / 25)
    - Roughrider Pipeline Company (correspondence only), 1981-1982 (Box-folder 29 / 26)
    - Shoshone Pipelines Ltd. (rates and valuations), 1960-1961 (Box-folder 29 / 27)
    - Teton Pipe Line Corp., 1961-1963 (Box-folder 29 / 28)
    - Texas Pipe Line Company (1969-1973 are monthly statements of operations), 1948-1973 (Box-folder 29 / 29-35)
    - Toronto Pipe Line Company (rate schedules), 1934-1953 (Box-folder 29 / 36)
    - Treasure State Pipe Line Company (Toole County), 1967 (Box-folder 309 / 1)
    - Western Oil Transportation Company (monthly statements of operations only), 1968-1973 (Box-folder 30 / 2-4)
    - Yellowstone Pipe Line Company (1969-1973 are monthly statements of operations), 1959-1973 (Box-folder 30 / 5-8)